<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
	Copyright (c) 2007 California Institute of Technology.
	ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. U.S. Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
	
	$Id$
	
	Author: Chris A. Mattmann
	Description: Product Type policy for eCAS that stores SELDI data
	provided by Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center (FHCRC).
-->
<cas:producttypes xmlns:cas="http://oodt.jpl.nasa.gov/1.0/cas">
	<type id="urn:edrn:SELDI_EVMSProcessedData" name="SELDI_EVMSProcessedData">
		<repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_ECAS_HOME]/products/seldi/processed/evms</repositoryPath>
		<versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.versioning.MetadataBasedFileVersioner</versionerClass>
		<description>Processed SELDI bioprocessor output from EVMS 
		(Eastern Virginia Medical School), EDRN Site 92. Comma delimited file (csv) generated using Cipehergen's 
		&quot;Peaks&quot; software. The baseline was smoothed using a window of 50 points and then subtracted 
		from each spectrum. The automatic peak detection mode was used in the Peaks software with the 
		following settings: minimum valley depth was set at 10 times the noise and the high sensitivity 
		of minimum valley depth was set at 0.5 times the noise. To eliminate those peaks were very close to the 
		baseline, the low sensitivity and high sensitivity of the peak height was set at 10 and 2 times the noise,
		respectively. The automatic peak detection slider was set at 8 for the mass region from 2 to 4 KDa, 11 
		for the mass region from 4 to 8 KDa, and 8 for the mass range from 8 to 40 KDa. Detected peaks and their 
		intensity values were then exported into excel spreadsheets.
		</description>
	    <metadata>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Title</key>
	        <val>SELDI EVMS Processed Data</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Date</key>
	        <val>2007-08-07T15:46:00.000Z</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Author</key>
	        <val>John Semmes</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>DataCustodian</key>
	        <val>Dale McLerran</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	         <key>ProtocolId</key>
	         <val>110</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>DatasetId</key>
	         <val>urn:edrn:SELDI_EVMSProcessedData</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>StudyObjective</key>
	         <val>It is then the goal of this collaborative project - EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational 
	         Collaboration (EPSIC) - to use state-of-the-art protein profiling technology to develop and 
	         validate such screening methods</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>SpecificAims</key>
	         <val>Specific Aim IA/Phase IA - The EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) 
	         will implement a process to synchronize SELDI output at the seven participating institutions 
	         using a single source of pooled normal sera (QC). Specific Aim IB/Phase IB - The EPSIC will 
	         synchronize SELDI output at the seven participating institutions using prostate cancer/control 
	         samples with verified presence of optimized diagnostic peaks. The reproducibility of QSTAR will 
	         also be determined using the same samples and compared to that of the PBS-II data. Specific Aim 
	         IC/Phase IC - The EPSIC will implement a seven-center collaboration to synchronize SELDI output 
	         using a new and expanded cohort of prostate cancer cases and controls obtained from all sites. 
	         The reproducibility of QSTAR will also be determined using the same samples and compared to that 
	         of the PBS-II data.</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>PlannedSampleSize</key>
	         <val>The EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) will implement a process to 
	         synchronize SELDI output at the seven participating institutions using a single source of pooled 
	         normal sera (QC). The target was to recruit 100 healthy males and 100 healthy females to donate 
	         two tubes of blood. Pregnant women and subjects less than 110 pounds were excluded from the blood 
	         collection. An IRB protocol was submitted two months in advance of the project. After IRB approval, 
	         fliers were generated and posted at many locations (e.g., EVMS, hospitals, doctor's offices). The 
	         blood was collected on November 6, 2002 from 7:30 am to 2:00 pm. A total of 360 healthy people (154 
	         male and 206 female) donated two tubes of blood each to make quality control (QC) serum.</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>SiteId</key>
	         <val>142</val>
	         <val>75</val>
	         <val>92</val>
	         <val>65</val>
	         <val>83</val>
	         <val>88</val>
	         <val>92</val>
	         <val>108</val>
	         <val>131</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>OrganId</key>
	         <val>16</val>
	       </keyval>
	    </metadata>
	 </type>   
	<type id="urn:edrn:SELDI_EVMSUnProcessedData" name="SELDI_EVMSUnProcessedData">
		<repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_ECAS_HOME]/products/seldi/unprocessed/evms</repositoryPath>
		<versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.versioning.MetadataBasedFileVersioner</versionerClass>
		<description>Unprocessed SELDI bioprocessor output from EVMS (Eastern Virginia Medical School), EDRN 
		Site 92. Each spectra was calibrated and normalized to an external coefficient of 0.2 using Ciphergen's 
		&quot;Peaks&quot; software. Raw time of flight values were then exported as combined spread sheets 	
		representing many individual spectra produced from serum samples in each study. These files are comma 
		delimited (csv).</description>
	    <metadata>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Title</key>
	        <val>SELDI EVMS UnProcessed Data</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Date</key>
	        <val>2007-08-07T15:46:00.000Z</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Author</key>
	        <val>John Semmes</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>DataCustodian</key>
	        <val>Dale McLerran</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	         <key>ProtocolId</key>
	         <val>110</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>DatasetId</key>
	         <val>urn:edrn:SELDI_EVMSUnProcessedData</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>StudyObjective</key>
	         <val>It is then the goal of this collaborative project - EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational 
	         Collaboration (EPSIC) - to use state-of-the-art protein profiling technology to develop and 
	         validate such screening methods</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>SpecificAims</key>
	         <val>Specific Aim IA/Phase IA - The EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) will 
	         implement a process to synchronize SELDI output at the seven participating institutions using a 
	         single source of pooled normal sera (QC). Specific Aim IB/Phase IB - The EPSIC will synchronize 	
	         SELDI output at the seven participating institutions using prostate cancer/control samples with 
	         verified presence of optimized diagnostic peaks. The reproducibility of QSTAR will also be determined 
	         using the same samples and compared to that of the PBS-II data. Specific Aim IC/Phase IC - The EPSIC will 
	         implement a seven-center collaboration to synchronize SELDI output using a new and expanded cohort of 
	         prostate cancer cases and controls obtained from all sites. The reproducibility of QSTAR will also be 
	         determined using the same samples and compared to that of the PBS-II data.</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>PlannedSampleSize</key>
	         <val>The EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) will implement a process to synchronize 
	         SELDI output at the seven participating institutions using a single source of pooled normal sera (QC). The 
	         target was to recruit 100 healthy males and 100 healthy females to donate two tubes of blood. Pregnant 
	         women and subjects less than 110 pounds were excluded from the blood collection. An IRB protocol was submitted 
	         two months in advance of the project. After IRB approval, fliers were generated and posted at many locations 
	         (e.g., EVMS, hospitals, doctor's offices). The blood was collected on November 6, 2002 from 7:30 am to 2:00 pm. 
	         A total of 360 healthy people (154 male and 206 female) donated two tubes of blood each to make quality control 
	         (QC) serum.</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>SiteId</key>
	         <val>142</val>
	         <val>75</val>
	         <val>92</val>
	         <val>65</val>
	         <val>83</val>
	         <val>88</val>
	         <val>92</val>
	         <val>108</val>
	         <val>131</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>OrganId</key>
	         <val>16</val>
	       </keyval>
	    </metadata>
	 </type>  
	<type id="urn:edrn:SELDI_UABProcessedData" name="SELDI_UABProcessedData">
		<repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_ECAS_HOME]/products/seldi/processed/uab</repositoryPath>
		<versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.versioning.MetadataBasedFileVersioner</versionerClass>
		<description>Processed SELDI bioprocessor output from UAB 
		(EDRN Site 75).
		</description>
	    <metadata>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Title</key>
	        <val>SELDI UAB Processed Data</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Date</key>
	        <val>2007-08-07T15:46:00.000Z</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>Author</key>
	        <val>Bill Grizzle</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	        <key>DataCustodian</key>
	        <val>Dale McLerran</val>
	      </keyval>
	      <keyval>
	         <key>ProtocolId</key>
	         <val>110</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>DatasetId</key>
	         <val>urn:edrn:SELDI_UABProcessedData</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>StudyObjective</key>
	         <val>It is then the goal of this collaborative project - EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration 
	         (EPSIC) - to use state-of-the-art protein profiling technology to develop and validate such screening methods.</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>SpecificAims</key>
	         <val>Specific Aim IA/Phase IA - The EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) will implement a 
	         process to synchronize SELDI output at the seven participating institutions using a single source of pooled normal 
	         sera (QC). Specific Aim IB/Phase IB - The EPSIC will synchronize SELDI output at the seven participating institutions 
	         using prostate cancer/control samples with verified presence of optimized diagnostic peaks. The reproducibility of 
	         QSTAR will also be determined using the same samples and compared to that of the PBS-II data. Specific Aim IC/Phase IC - 
	         The EPSIC will implement a seven-center collaboration to synchronize SELDI output using a new and expanded cohort of 
	         prostate cancer cases and controls obtained from all sites. The reproducibility of QSTAR will also be determined using the 
	         same samples and compared to that of the PBS-II data.</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>PlannedSampleSize</key>
	         <val>The EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) will implement a process to synchronize SELDI output 
	         at the seven participating institutions using a single source of pooled normal sera (QC). The target was to recruit 100 
	         healthy males and 100 healthy females to donate two tubes of blood. Pregnant women and subjects less than 110 pounds were
	         excluded from the blood collection. An IRB protocol was submitted two months in advance of the project. After IRB approval, 
	         fliers were generated and posted at many locations (e.g., EVMS, hospitals, doctor's offices). The blood was collected on November 
	         6, 2002 from 7:30 am to 2:00 pm. A total of 360 healthy people (154 male and 206 female) donated two tubes of blood each to make 
	         quality control (QC) serum.</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>SiteId</key>
	         <val>142</val>
	         <val>75</val>
	         <val>92</val>
	         <val>65</val>
	         <val>83</val>
	         <val>88</val>
	         <val>92</val>
	         <val>108</val>
	         <val>131</val>
	       </keyval>
	       <keyval>
	         <key>OrganId</key>
	         <val>16</val>
	       </keyval>
	    </metadata>
	 </type>
</cas:producttypes>