<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2010 California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. U.S. Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  
  $Id$
  
  Author(s): Chris A. Mattmann, Kristen Anton, Heather Kincaid
  Description: Product Type policy for PLCO datasets.
-->

<cas:producttypes xmlns:cas="http://oodt.jpl.nasa.gov/1.0/cas">

  <type id="urn:edrn:BGWHCramerPLCOPhaseIIIAnalysis" 
        name="BGWHCramerPLCOPhaseIIIAnalysis">
   <repository path="file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive" />
   <versioner class="gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner" />
    <description>PLCO Phase III Analysis Files</description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="org.apache.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
      <extractor class="org.apache.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.examples.MimeTypeExtractor" />
      <extractor class="org.apache.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.examples.FinalFileLocationExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!-- this property specifies whether you want the FILE_LOCATION field
               computed by this extractor to replace any other FILE_LOCATION met 
               attribute.
           -->
           <property name="replace" value="true"/>
        </configuration>
      </extractor>   
    </metExtractors>
    <!--  fixed for all products of this type = ecas + esis meta excel spreadsheet -->
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetName</key>
        <val>PLCO Phase III Dataset</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2010-02-28T08:55:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>Daniel Cramer</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Allison Vitonis</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>AVITONIS@PARTNERS.ORG</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>PLCO datasets (Phase III):
        
        The Phase III study was coordinated by the PLCO.  Sample collection, processing, shipping and storage were standardized across 
        all screening sites.  Briefly, blood was drawn and processed within 2 hours into vials (~1.8ml) of serum/plasma, buffy coat and 
        red blood cells. A unique specimen identification number was generated for each vial and daughter vial created.  Vials were 
        stored at -70 °C and shipped to the central biorepository overnight on dry ice for long-term storage at -70°C or -157 °C. 
        By June of 2006, 118 cases of invasive ovarian, primary peritoneal, and fallopian tube cancers with available samples had been 
        confirmed. Tumors of “borderline malignancy” were excluded.    Serum samples most proximate to diagnosis were selected.  Controls 
        were selected from a pool of healthy individuals who remained cancer free and were matched to cases by five year age categories at 
        blood draw, calendar year of blood draw.  Women who reported a history of cancer or oophorectomy at baseline were excluded from control 
        selection. For each case, 8 healthy controls were selected: 4 randomly selected from a pool of all eligible controls and representing 
        general population controls; 2 with positive family history of breast or ovarian cancer; and 2 with history of an elevated CA125.  Sixty 
        replicate pairs were randomly inserted into the batches for blinded QC; ten pairs of which had CA125 values greater than 25 U/ml.  
        
        PLCO serum samples to be allocated are at the PLCO biorepository in Frederick, Md. One vial containing 1.8ml of serum was pulled from the 
        PLCO biorepository for each selected subject and was sent to the PLCO central processing lab for aliquoting. Aliquots of desired amounts 
        for each investigator teams were made side by side in small batches to avoid repeated freeze-thaw, and to minimize variability in handling.  
        FHCRC received 0.3 ml, MDACC 0.1 ml, Partners two 0.6ml aliquots, and Pittsburgh 0.2 ml, and YUSM 0.2 ml.  Aliquots were labeled with a 
        unique sample ID, and were randomly ordered such that cases and controls were evenly distributed, then packed into 81-cell freezer boxes 
        and kept frozen. Prior to shipping, the laboratories were notified of the shipment 24 hours in advance. Aliquots were shipped overnight on 
        dry ice.  A shipping manifest containing aliquot IDs was included in the package and was also emailed to the laboratories.  Each laboratory 
        received aliquots of identical sets of samples. 
        
        Laboratory Assays
        
        Laboratory assays for the phase III PLCO study were conducted at the four separate laboratories by individuals who were blind to case or control 
        status for both the phase II and phase III specimens.  Assays included single- or multi-plex Luminex bead assays, plate-based ELISA assays, platform-based 
        (Roche E170) assays, and a mass spectroscopy-based system using surface enhanced antibody chips.  With the exceptions noted below, the assays used for 
        the phase III specimens were also used for the phase II specimens.
        
        At FHCRC single-plex Luminex bead assays were used for all markers, details of which can be found in (Shah CA, Lowe KA, Paley P, Wallace E, Anderson GL, McIntosh MW, 
        Andersen MR, Scholler N, Bergan LA, Thorpe JD, Urban N, and Drescher CW, Influence of ovarian cancer risk status on the diagnostic performance of the serum biomarkers 
        mesothelin, HE4, and CA125. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev, 2009. 18(5): p. 1365-72.).   The same assays were carried over into phase III except that a plate based 
        assay for MMP-7 was introduced.  MDACC used a mass spectroscopy based system for its markers in both phases  further described in (Zhang Z, Bast RC, Jr., Yu Y, Li J, 
        Sokoll LJ, Rai AJ, Rosenzweig JM, Cameron B, Wang YY, Meng XY, Berchuck A, Van Haaften-Day C, Hacker NF, de Bruijn HW, van der Zee AG, Jacobs IJ, Fung ET, and Chan DW, 
        Three biomarkers identified from serum proteomic analysis for the detection of early stage ovarian cancer. Cancer Res, 2004. 64(16): p. 5882-90.).    Partners used plate-based 
        assay for B7-H4(Diadexus), DcR3(Diadexus), CA72.4, IGF 2, Mesothelin, HE4, and Kallikrein 6 (as described in (Diamandis EP, Scorilas A, Fracchioli S, Van Gramberen M, De Bruijn H, 
        Henrik A, Soosaipillai A, Grass L, Yousef GM, Stenman UH, Massobrio M, Van Der Zee AG, Vergote I, and Katsaros D, Human kallikrein 6 (hK6): a new potential serum biomarker for 
        diagnosis and prognosis of ovarian carcinoma. J Clin Oncol, 2003. 21(6): p. 1035-43)).  Platform-based assays (Roche) were used for CA125, CA15.3, CA19.9, and CEA.  Unless the volume 
        was insufficient assays were run in duplicate and averaged.  Seven markers were carried over to phase III and these included B7H4, CA125, CA15.3, CA19.9, CA72.4, HE4, and HK 6.   
        The same assays were used except that a platform-based assay was available for CA72.4.   The two 0.3 aliquots were first combined and homogenized.  UPCI used a multi-plex bead 
        assay system was used to evaluate 34 markers in phase II.  This technique is described in (Nolen B, Marrangoni A, Velikokhatnaya L, Prosser D, Winans M, Gorelik E, and Lokshin A, 
        A serum based analysis of ovarian epithelial tumorigenesis. Gynecol Oncol, 2009. 112(1): p. 47-54).  For phase III, the number of markers was reduced to 8 but the same technique 
        was used.  For the phase II markers included in the Yale panel, these markers were evaluated using a multi-plex bead system described in (Visintin I, Feng Z, Longton G, Ward DC, 
        Alvero AB, Lai Y, Tenthorey J, Leiser A, Flores-Saaib R, Yu H, Azori M, Rutherford T, Schwartz PE, and Mor G, Diagnostic markers for early detection of ovarian cancer. Clin Cancer
        Res, 2008. 14(4): p. 1065-72).  For the phase III specimens the same markers were carried over but the analyses were performed by Laboratory Corporation of America.
      </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndConclusionSummary</key>
        <val>The PLCO datasets contain 35 markers measured by five sites (Partners, FHCRC, MD Anderson, Pittsburgh, and Yale)</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>Breast/GYN</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolName</key>
        <val>312</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolID</key>
        <val>312</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:BGWHCramerPLCOPhaseIIIAnalysis</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DateDatasetFrozen</key>
        <val>N/A</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
		<val>70</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>PubMedID</key>
		<val>N/A</val>
      </keyval>
 	  <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Ovary</val>
      </keyval>
    <keyval>
       <key>QAState</key>
       <val>Accepted</val>
    </keyval>
    <keyval>
        <key>PublishState</key>
        <val>yes</val>
    </keyval>
    <keyval type="vector">
       <key>AccessGrantedTo</key>
       <val>Breast and Gynecologic</val>
       <val>Super User</val>
    </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
        NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
        NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
        In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>
  
  
</cas:producttypes>
