<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cas:metadata xmlns:cas="http://oodt.jpl.nasa.gov/1.0/cas">
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>SiteId</key>
  <val>63</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PI</key>
  <val>Barker, Peter E., Ph.D., M.S., B.A.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Institution</key>
  <val>National Institute of Standards and Technology</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyId</key>
  <val>63-Barker-1</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
 <key>StudyDescription</key>
 <val>To standardize a fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) modification of the 
 mutagen sensitivity assay (MSA), scoring criteria were evaluated by web-based validation.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyBackground</key>
  <val><![CDATA[In chromosome breakage assays, validated, universal criteria for selection of cells 
  and classification of chromosome aberrations may enhance their utility for cancer susceptibility 
  screening. To standardize a fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) modification of the mutagen 
  sensitivity assay (MSA), scoring criteria were evaluated by web-based validation. Two hundred digital 
  FISH images were assigned random identification numbers. With this set of images, criteria for inclusion 
  of cells and measurement of the frequency of abnormal cells were evaluated by eight observers, all of 
  whom had five or more years of experience. Observers included doctoral and MS/BS level cytogeneticists, 
  and were drawn from a randomized pool of 54 volunteers. Questions addressed were: (1) how uniformly were 
  criteria applied to analysis of a standard digital FISH image set and (2) did concordance vary with 
  educational level? These data suggest inter-rater agreement within a factor of 2 for average breakage 
  frequency, but revealed greater variability in cell selection. These results aid in estimating the 
  components of assay variance due to definitions, technical parameters and biological variables.]]></val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyMethods</key>
  <val>Two hundred digital FISH images were assigned random identification numbers. With this set of 
  images, criteria for inclusion of cells and measurement of the frequency of abnormal cells were evaluated 
  by eight observers, all of whom had five or more years of experience.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyResults</key>
  <val>inter-rater agreement within a factor of 2 for average breakage frequency, but revealed greater 
  variability in cell selection. These results aid in estimating the components of assay variance due 
  to definitions, technical parameters and biological variables.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>GrantSupport</key>
  <val>Y1-CN-010-01</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationId</key>
  <val>63-Barker-1-PMID15279836</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationAuthors</key>
  <val>Barker PE</val>
  <val>Wang W</val>
  <val>Wagner PD</val>
  <val>Pinsky P</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationContact</key>
  <val>peter.barker@nist.gov</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationTitle</key>
  <val>Inter-rater agreement on chromosome 5 breakage in FISH-based mutagen sensitivity assays (MSAs)</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Journal</key>
  <val>Mutat Res. 2004 Aug 8; 562(1-2):133-42.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationPubMedId</key>
  <val>15279836</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>AnalysisId</key>
  <val>63-Barker-1-MSA</val>
</keyval> 
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Technology</key>
  <val>FISH-based mutagen sensitivity assays (MSAs)</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolType</key>
  <val>Mutagen Sensitivity Assays</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolDescription</key>
  <val>Validation of the Mutagen Sensitivity and Chromosomal Hotspot Assays</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Organism</key>
  <val>Human</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Specimen</key>
  <val>Blood</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyType</key>
  <val>Mutagen Sensitivity, Cancer Susceptibility</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>AnalysisType</key>
  <val>FISH-based mutagen sensitivity asssys</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>MarkerType</key>
  <val>Genetic</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>SpecimenType</key>
  <val>Blood</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ResearchType</key>
  <val>chromosomal</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProductType</key>
  <val>FishData</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>FileLocation</key>
  <val>/some/path</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Filename</key>
  <val>some_name</val>
</keyval>
</cas:metadata>