<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cas:metadata xmlns:cas="http://oodt.jpl.nasa.gov/1.0/cas">
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>SiteId</key>
  <val>192</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PI</key>
  <val>Liu, Alvin Y., Ph.D.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Institution</key>
  <val>University of Washington</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyId</key>
  <val>192-Liu-2</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
 <key> StudyDescription</key>
 <val>We are investigating the molecular basis of cell-cell interaction in the 
 differentiation of epithelial cells of the human bladder. Our approach involves 
 cell-type identification by CD cell surface molecules, isolation of specific cell 
 populations, gene expression analysis, and functional test of candidate genes in a 
 cell culture system.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyBackground</key>
  <val><![CDATA[Stromal mesenchyme cells play an important role in epithelial differentiation 
  and likely in cancer as well. Induction of epithelial differentiation is organ-specific, and 
  the genes responsible could be identified through a comparative genomic analysis of the stromal 
  cells from two different organs. These genes might be aberrantly expressed in cancer since cancer 
  could be viewed as due to a defect in stromal signaling. We propose to identify the prostate stromal 
  genes by analysis of differentially expressed genes between prostate and bladder stromal cells, and 
  to examine their expression in prostate cancer.]]></val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyMethods</key>
  <val>Immunohistochemistry using antibodies to cluster designation (CD) cell surface antigens was 
  first used to characterize the stromas of the prostate and bladder. Stromal cells were prepared from 
  either prostate or bladder tissue for cell culture. RNA was isolated from the cultured cells and analyzed 
  by DNA microarrays. Expression of candidate genes in normal prostate and prostate cancer was examined by RT-PCR. </val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyResults</key>
  <val><![CDATA[The bladder stroma was phenotypically different from that of the prostate. Most notable was the presence 
  of a layer of CD13+ cells adjacent to the urothelium. This structural feature was also seen in the mouse bladder. The 
  prostate stroma was uniformly CD13-. A number of differentially expressed genes between prostate and bladder stromal 
  cells were identified. One prostate gene, proenkephalin (PENK), was of interest because it encodes a hormone. Secreted 
  proteins such as hormones and bioactive peptides are known to mediate cell-cell signaling. Prostate stromal expression 
  of PENK was verified by an antibody raised against a PENK peptide, by RT-PCR analysis of laser-capture microdissected 
  stromal cells, and by database analysis. Gene expression analysis showed that PENK expression was down-regulated in prostate cancer.]]></val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyConclusion</key>
  <val>Our findings show that the histologically similar stromas of the prostate and bladder are phenotypically different, 
  and express organ-specific genes. The importance of these genes in epithelial development is suggested by their abnormal 
  expression in cancer. Among the candidates is the hormone PENK and the down-regulation of PENK expression in cancer suggests 
  a possible association with cancer development.</val>
 </keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ResearchSupport</key>
  <val>N.I.H., Extramural</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>GrantSupport</key>
  <val>CA85859/CA/NCI</val>
  <val>CA98699/CA/NCI</val>
  <val>DK63630/DK/NIDDK</val>
  <val>DK65260/DK/NIDDK</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationId</key>
  <val>192-Liu-2-PMID16343351</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationAuthors</key>
  <val>Goo YA</val>
  <val>Goodlett DR</val>
  <val>Pascal LE</val>
  <val>Worthington KD</val>
  <val>Vessella RL</val>
  <val>True LD</val>
  <val>Liu AY</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationContact</key>
  <val>Department of Urology, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA. youngah@u.washington.edu</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationTitle</key>
  <val>Stromal mesenchyme cell genes of the human prostate and bladder.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Journal</key>
  <val>BMC Urol. 2005 Dec 12;5:17.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationPubMedId</key>
  <val>16343351</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>AnalysisId</key>
  <val>192-Liu-2-IHC-Prostate</val>
</keyval> 
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>AnalysisDescription</key>
  <val>CD marker expression profile of prostate cancer cells for investigating the molecular basis 
  of cell-cell interaction in the differentiation of epithelial cells of the human</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Technology</key>
  <val>Immunohistochemistry</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolId</key>
  <val>UESC Specimen Prep 1</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolType</key>
  <val>Immunoassay</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Software</key>
  <val>Predictive Value of Tests; ROC Curve</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolType</key>
  <val>Immunostain Specimen Preparation</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolDescription</key>
  <val>http://scgap.systemsbiology.net/resources/protocols.php</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Organism</key>
  <val>Human</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>OrganSite</key>
  <val>Prostate</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Specimen</key>
  <val>Prostate Tissue</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ClinicalDiagnosis</key>
  <val>Prostate Cancer</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>DiagnosisDescription</key>
  <val>Prostate Adenocarinoma</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyType</key>
  <val>Prostate/cytology</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>AnalysisType</key>
  <val>Gene Expression</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>MarkerType</key>
  <val>Stromal Cells</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>SpecimenType</key>
  <val>Cells, Cultured</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Gender</key>
  <val>Male</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ResearchType</key>
  <val>Prostatic Neoplasms/genetics</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProductType</key>
  <val>ImmunohistochemistryData</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>FileLocation</key>
  <val>/some/path</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Filename</key>
  <val>some_name</val>
</keyval>
</cas:metadata>