<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cas:metadata xmlns:cas="http://oodt.jpl.nasa.gov/1.0/cas">
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>SiteId</key>
  <val>92</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PI</key>
  <val>John Semmes, Ph.D.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Institution</key>
  <val>Eastern Virginia Medical School</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyId</key>
  <val>92-Semmes-1</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
 <key>StudyDescription</key>
 <val>The goal of the EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) is to use state-of-the-art 
 protein profiling technology to further develop and validate a serum-based screening method for prostate cancer.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyBackground</key>
  <val><![CDATA[Protein expression profiling for differences indicative of early cancer has promise for improving 
  diagnostics. This report describes the first stage of a National Cancer Institute/Early Detection Research 
  Network-sponsored multiinstitutional evaluation and validation of this approach for detection of prostate cancer.]]></val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyMethods</key>
  <val><![CDATA[Two sequential experimental phases were conducted to establish interlaboratory calibration and standardization 
  of the surface-enhanced laser desorption (SELDI) instrumental and assay platform output. We first established whether 
  the output from multiple calibrated Protein Biosystem II SELDI-ionization time-of-flight mass spectrometry (TOF-MS) 
  instruments demonstrated acceptable interlaboratory reproducibility. This was determined by measuring mass accuracy, 
  resolution, signal-to-noise ratio, and normalized intensity of three m/z "peaks" present in a standard pooled serum 
  sample. We next evaluated the ability of the calibrated and standardized instrumentation to accurately differentiate 
  between selected cases of prostate cancer and control by use of an algorithm developed from data derived from a single 
  site 2 years earlier.]]>
</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyResults</key>
  <val><![CDATA[When the described standard operating procedures were established at all laboratory sites, the across-laboratory 
  measurements revealed a CV for mass accuracy of 0.1%, signal-to-noise ratio of 40%, and normalized intensity of 15-36% 
  for the three pooled serum peaks. This was comparable to the intralaboratory measurements of the same peaks. The instrument 
  systems were then challenged with sera from a selected group of 14 cases and 14 controls. The classification agreement 
  between each site and the established decision algorithm were examined by use of both raw peak intensity boosting and ranked 
  peak intensity boosting. All six sites achieved perfect blinded classification for all samples when boosted alignment of raw 
  intensities was used. Four of six sites achieved perfect blinded classification with ranked intensities, with one site passing 
  the criteria of 26 of 28 correct and one site failing with 19 of 28 correct.]]>
</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyConclusion</key>
  <val><![CDATA[These results demonstrate that "between-laboratory" reproducibility of SELDI-TOF-MS serum profiling approaches that of 
  "within-laboratory" reproducibility as determined by measuring discrete m/z peaks over time and across laboratories.]]></val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationId</key>
  <val>92-Semmes-1</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationAuthors</key>
  <val>Semmes OJ</val>
  <val>Feng Z</val>
  <val>Adam BL</val>
  <val>Banez LL</val>
  <val>Bigbee WL</val>
  <val>Campos D</val>
  <val>Cazares LH</val>
  <val>Chan DW</val>
  <val>Grizzle WE</val>
  <val>Izbicka E</val>
  <val>Kagan J</val>
  <val>Malik G</val>
  <val>McLerran D</val>
  <val>Moul JW</val>
  <val>Partin A</val>
  <val>Prasanna P</val>
  <val>Rosenzweig J</val>
  <val>Sokoll LJ</val>
  <val>Srivastava S</val>
  <val>Thompson I</val>
  <val>Welsh MJ</val>
  <val>White N</val>
  <val>Winget M</val>
  <val>Yasui Y</val>
  <val>Zhang Z</val>
  <val>Zhu L</val>
  
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationContact</key>
  <val>semmesoj@evms.edu</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationTitle</key>
  <val>Evaluation of serum protein profiling by surface-enhanced laser desorption/ionization 
  time-of-flight mass spectrometry for the detection of prostate cancer: I. Assessment of platform reproducibility.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Journal</key>
  <val>Clin Chem. 2005 Jan;51(1):102-12.</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>PublicationPubMedId</key>
  <val>15613711</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Technology</key>
  <val><![CDATA[SELDI-TOF-MS, Protein Biosystem II model outfitted with the metal affinity (IMAC3-Cu) 
  ProteinChip®, Biomek® 2000 Workstation liquid-handling robot (Beckman Instruments)]]></val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolType</key>
  <val>Protein profiling</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProtocolDescription</key>
  <val>SELDI Phase I: Assay Validation-Prostate</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Organism</key>
  <val>Human</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>OrganSite</key>
  <val>Prostate</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Specimen</key>
  <val>Serum</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>StudyType</key>
  <val>Protein Profiling</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ClinicalDiagnosis</key>
  <val>Prostate Carcinoma</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>AnalysisType</key>
  <val>SELDI-TOF-MS</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>MarkerType</key>
  <val>Protein</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Gender</key>
  <val>Male</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>ProductType</key>
  <val>MassSpecData</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>FileLocation</key>
  <val>/some/path</val>
</keyval>
<keyval type="vector">
  <key>Filename</key>
  <val>some_name</val>
</keyval>
</cas:metadata>