<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
  Copyright (c) 2008 California Institute of Technology.
  ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. U.S. Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
  
  $Id$
  
  Author(s): Chris A. Mattmann, John J. Tran, and Heather L. Kincaid 
  
  Description: Product Type policy for miscellaneous data sets acquired
  from EDRN PIs by Tina Xiao.
-->

<cas:producttypes xmlns:cas="http://oodt.jpl.nasa.gov/1.0/cas">
  <type id="urn:edrn:UWashTransProfileMicroarrayData" name="UWashTransProfileMicroarrayData">
    <repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive</repositoryPath>
    <versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner</versionerClass>
    <description>Transcriptome profiling experiments with LNCaP and C4-2 human prostate cancer cell lines 
    with the aim of identifying genes associated with prostate cancer progression.
    </description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
    </metExtractors>
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetName</key>
        <val>University of Washington Microarray data.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2008-06-24T20:12:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>Prostate and Urologic</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>Alvin Liu</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Tina Xiao</val>
      </keyval>
      
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianPhone</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>AnalyticMethods</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDesign</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>EligibilityCriteria</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndColclusionSummary</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      
      
     <keyval>
         <key>StudyBackground</key>
         <val><![CDATA[Affymetrix GeneChip Array and Massively Parallel Signature Sequencing (MPSS) 
         are two high throughput methodologies used to profile transcriptomes. Each method has certain 
         strengths and weaknesses; however, no comparison has been made between the data derived from Affymetrix 
         arrays and MPSS. In this study, two lineage-related prostate cancer cell lines, LNCaP and C4-2, were 
         used for transcriptome analysis with the aim of identifying genes associated with prostate cancer progression.]]>
         </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>StudyMethods</key>
        <val>Affymetrix GeneChip array and MPSS analyses were performed. Data was analyzed with GeneSpring 6.2 
        and in-house perl scripts. Expression array results were verified with RT-PCR.
        </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>StudyResults</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Comparison of the data revealed that both technologies detected genes the other did not. 
        In LNCaP, 3,180 genes were only detected by Affymetrix and 1,169 genes were only detected by MPSS. Similarly, 
        in C4-2, 4,121 genes were only detected by Affymetrix and 1,014 genes were only detected by MPSS. Analysis of the 
        combined transcriptomes identified 66 genes unique to LNCaP cells and 33 genes unique to C4-2 cells. Expression 
        analysis of these genes in prostate cancer specimens showed CA1 to be highly expressed in bone metastasis but not 
        expressed in primary tumor and EPHA7 to be expressed in normal prostate and primary tumor but not bone metastasis.]]>
        </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>StudyConclusion</key>
        <val>Our data indicates that transcriptome profiling with a single methodology will not fully assess the expression of all genes in a cell line. A combination of transcription profiling technologies such as DNA array and MPSS provides a more robust means to assess the expression profile of an RNA sample. Finally, genes that were differentially expressed in cell lines were also differentially expressed in primary prostate cancer and its metastases.
        </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>ResearchSupport</key>
        <val>N.I.H., Extramural</val>
        <val>Non-U.S. Gov't</val>
        <val>U.S. Gov't, P.H.S</val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>GrantSupport</key>
        <val>CA85859/CA/NCI</val>
        <val>CA98699/CA/NCI</val>
        <val>DK63630/DK/NIDDK</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtcolName</key>
        <val>114</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:UWashTransProfileMicroarrayData</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
        <val>192</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Prostate</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>

  <type id="urn:edrn:UWashImmunohistochemistryData" name="UWashImmunohistochemistryData">
    <repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive</repositoryPath>
    <versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner</versionerClass>
    <description>Data capturing investigation of the molecular basis of cell-cell interaction in the differentiation 
    of epithelial cells of the human bladder. The approach involves cell-type identification by CD cell surface molecules,
    isolation of specific cell populations, gene expression analysis, and functional 
    test of candidate genes in a cell culture system.</description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
    </metExtractors>
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetName</key>
        <val>University of Washington Immunohistochemistry data.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2008-06-24T20:12:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>Alvin Liu</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>Prostate and Urologic</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Tina Xiao</val>
      </keyval>
      
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianPhone</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>AnalyticMethods</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDesign</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>EligibilityCriteria</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndColclusionSummary</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
  
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDescription</key>
        <val><![CDATA[We are investigating the molecular basis of cell-cell interaction in the 
        differentiation of epithelial cells of the human bladder. Our approach involves 
        cell-type identification by CD cell surface molecules, isolation of specific cell 
        populations, gene expression analysis, and functional test of candidate genes in a 
        cell culture system.]]>
        </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>StudyBackground</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Stromal mesenchyme cells play an important role in epithelial differentiation 
        and likely in cancer as well. Induction of epithelial differentiation is organ-specific, and 
        the genes responsible could be identified through a comparative genomic analysis of the stromal 
        cells from two different organs. These genes might be aberrantly expressed in cancer since cancer 
        could be viewed as due to a defect in stromal signaling. We propose to identify the prostate stromal 
        genes by analysis of differentially expressed genes between prostate and bladder stromal cells, and 
        to examine their expression in prostate cancer.]]>
        </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>StudyMethods</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Immunohistochemistry using antibodies to cluster designation (CD) cell surface antigens was 
        first used to characterize the stromas of the prostate and bladder. Stromal cells were prepared from 
        either prostate or bladder tissue for cell culture. RNA was isolated from the cultured cells and analyzed 
        by DNA microarrays. Expression of candidate genes in normal prostate and prostate cancer was examined by RT-PCR.]]>
        </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>StudyResults</key>
        <val><![CDATA[The bladder stroma was phenotypically different from that of the prostate. Most notable was the presence 
        of a layer of CD13+ cells adjacent to the urothelium. This structural feature was also seen in the mouse bladder. The 
        prostate stroma was uniformly CD13-. A number of differentially expressed genes between prostate and bladder stromal 
        cells were identified. One prostate gene, proenkephalin (PENK), was of interest because it encodes a hormone. Secreted 
        proteins such as hormones and bioactive peptides are known to mediate cell-cell signaling. Prostate stromal expression 
        of PENK was verified by an antibody raised against a PENK peptide, by RT-PCR analysis of laser-capture microdissected 
        stromal cells, and by database analysis. Gene expression analysis showed that PENK expression was down-regulated in prostate cancer.]]>
        </val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>StudyConclusion</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Our findings show that the histologically similar stromas of the prostate and bladder are phenotypically different, 
        and express organ-specific genes. The importance of these genes in epithelial development is suggested by their abnormal 
        expression in cancer. Among the candidates is the hormone PENK and the down-regulation of PENK expression in cancer suggests 
        a possible association with cancer development.]]>
        </val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
         <key>ResearchSupport</key>
         <val>N.I.H., Extramural</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
         <key>GrantSupport</key>
         <val>CA85859/CA/NCI</val>
         <val>CA98699/CA/NCI</val>
         <val>DK63630/DK/NIDDK</val>
         <val>DK65260/DK/NIDDK</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolName</key>
        <val>201</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:UWashImmunohistochemistryData</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
        <val>192</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Prostate</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>
  
  <type id="urn:edrn:UPittLabMAPOvarianData" name="UPittLabMAPOvarianData">
    <repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive</repositoryPath>
    <versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner</versionerClass>
    <description>Ovarian cancer biomarker discovery study data using multianalyte LabMAP profiling.</description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
    </metExtractors> 
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetName</key>
        <val>University of Pittsburg Ovarian data.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2008-06-24T20:12:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>Anna Lokshin</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>Breast/GYN</val>
      </keyval>      
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Tina Xiao</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianPhone</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>AnalyticMethods</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDesign</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>EligibilityCriteria</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndColclusionSummary</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyBackground</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Early detection of ovarian cancer might improve 
        clinical outcome. Some studies have shown the role of cytokines as a 
        new group of tumor markers for ovarian cancer. We hypothesized that a 
        panel comprised of multiple cytokines, which individually may not show 
        strong correlation with the disease, might provide higher diagnostic power.]]>
        </val>
       </keyval>
       <keyval>
        <key>StudyMethods</key>
        <val>To evaluate the diagnostic utility of cytokine panel, we used a novel multianalyte 
        LabMAP profiling technology that allows simultaneous measurement of multiple 
        markers.
        </val>
       </keyval>
       <keyval>
        <key>StudyResults</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Concentrations of 24 cytokines (cytokines/chemokines, growth, and angiogenic 
        factors) in combination with cancer antigen-125 (CA-125), were measured in sera of 44 patients 
        with early-stage ovarian cancer, 45 healthy women, and 37 patients with benign pelvic tumors. 
        Six markers, i.e., interleukin (IL)-6, IL-8, epidermal growth factor (EGF), vascular endothelial 
        growth factor (VEGF), monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 (MCP-1), and CA-125, showed significant 
        differences in serum concentrations between ovarian cancer and control groups. Out of this group, 
        IL-6, IL-8, VEGF, EGF, and CA-125, were used in a classification tree analysis that resulted in 
        84 percent sensitivity at 95 percent specificity. The receiver operator characteristic curve created using the 
        combination of markers produced sensitivities between 90 percent and 100 percent in the area of 80 percent to 90 percent 
        specificity, whereas the receiver operator characteristic curve for CA-125 alone resulted in 
        sensitivities of 70 percent to 80 percent. The classification tree analysis for discrimination of benign 
        condition from ovarian cancer used CA-125, granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF), IL-6, 
        EGF, and VEGF resulting in 86.5 percent sensitivity and 93.0 percent specificity.]]>
        </val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyConclusion</key>
        <val>The presented data show that simultaneous testing of a panel of serum cytokines and CA-125 
        using LabMAP technology may present a promising approach for ovarian cancer detection.
        </val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResearchSupport</key>
        <val>N N.I.H., Extramural</val>
        <val>U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</val>
        <val>U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</val>
     </keyval>
     <keyval>
        <key>GrantSupport</key>
        <val>1R01 CA098642-01A1/CA/NCI</val>
        <val>R03 CA102888/CA/NCI</val>
     </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolName</key>
        <val>119</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:UPittLabMAPOvarianData</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
        <val>5</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Ovary</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>
  
  <type id="urn:edrn:UPittLabMAPPancreaticData" name="UPittLabMAPPancreaticData">
    <repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive</repositoryPath>
    <versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner</versionerClass>
    <description>Pancreatic cancer biomarker discovery study using multianalyte LabMAP profiling.</description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
    </metExtractors>
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetname</key>
        <val>University of Pittsburg Pancreatic data.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2008-06-24T20:12:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>Anna Lokshin</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Tina Xiao</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianPhone</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>AnalyticMethods</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDesign</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>EligibilityCriteria</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndColclusionSummary</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>GI and Other Associated</val>
      </keyval>   
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyBackground</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Early detection of pancreatic cancer might improve clinical outcome. Some studies 
        have shown the role of cytokines as a new group of tumor markers for pancreatic cancer. We hypothesized 
        that a panel comprised of multiple cytokines, which individually may not show strong correlation with 
        the disease, might provide higher diagnostic power.]]></val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyMethods</key>
        <val>To evaluate the diagnostic utility of cytokine panel, we used a novel multianalyte LabMAP 
        profiling technology that allows simultaneous measurement of multiple markers.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyConclusion</key>
        <val>The presented data show that simultaneous testing of a panel of serum cytokines and CA-125 
        using LabMAP technology may present a promising approach for pancreatic cancer detection.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResearchSupport</key>
        <val>N N.I.H., Extramural</val>
        <val>U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S</val>
        <val>U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>GrantSupport</key>
        <val>1R01 CA098642-01A1/CA/NCI</val>
        <val>R03 CA102888/CA/NCI</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolName</key>
        <val>234</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:UPittLabMAPPancreaticData</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
        <val>167</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Pancreas</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>
  
  <type id="urn:edrn:DukeLabMAPBreastData" name="DukeLabMAPBreastData">
    <repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive</repositoryPath>
    <versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner</versionerClass>
    <description>Breast cancer biomarker discovery study using multianalyte LabMAP profiling.</description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
    </metExtractors>
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetName</key>
        <val>Duke University Breast data.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2008-06-24T20:12:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>Jeffrey Marks</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianPhone</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>AnalyticMethods</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDesign</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>EligibilityCriteria</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndColclusionSummary</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Tina Xiao</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>Breast/GYN</val>
      </keyval>   
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyBackground</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Early detection of breast cancer might improve clinical outcome. Some studies have 
        shown the role of cytokines as a new group of tumor markers for breast cancer. We hypothesized 
        that a panel comprised of multiple cytokines, which individually may not show strong correlation 
        with the disease, might provide higher diagnostic power.]]></val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyMethods</key>
        <val>To evaluate the diagnostic utility of cytokine panel, we used a novel multianalyte LabMAP profiling 
        technology that allows simultaneous measurement of multiple markers.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolName</key>
        <val>70</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:DukeLabMAPBreastData</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
        <val>81</val>     
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Breast</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>
  
  <type id="urn:edrn:NISTFishMSAData" name="NISTFishMSAData">
    <repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive</repositoryPath>
    <versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner</versionerClass>
    <description><![CDATA[In chromosome breakage assays, validated, universal criteria for selection of cells 
  and classification of chromosome aberrations may enhance their utility for cancer susceptibility 
  screening. To standardize a fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) modification of the mutagen 
  sensitivity assay (MSA), scoring criteria were evaluated by web-based validation. Two hundred digital 
  FISH images were assigned random identification numbers. With this set of images, criteria for inclusion 
  of cells and measurement of the frequency of abnormal cells were evaluated by eight observers, all of 
  whom had five or more years of experience. Observers included doctoral and MS/BS level cytogeneticists, 
  and were drawn from a randomized pool of 54 volunteers. Questions addressed were: (1) how uniformly were 
  criteria applied to analysis of a standard digital FISH image set and (2) did concordance vary with 
  educational level? These data suggest inter-rater agreement within a factor of 2 for average breakage 
  frequency, but revealed greater variability in cell selection. These results aid in estimating the 
  components of assay variance due to definitions, technical parameters and biological variables.]]>
  </description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
    </metExtractors>
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetName</key>
        <val>NIST Fish data.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2008-06-24T20:12:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>Peter Barker</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Tina Xiao</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianPhone</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>AnalyticMethods</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDesign</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>EligibilityCriteria</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndColclusionSummary</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>N/A</val>
      </keyval>   
      <keyval>
       <key>StudyDescription</key>
       <val>To standardize a fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) modification of the 
       mutagen sensitivity assay (MSA), scoring criteria were evaluated by web-based validation.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyBackground</key>
        <val><![CDATA[In chromosome breakage assays, validated, universal criteria for selection of cells 
        and classification of chromosome aberrations may enhance their utility for cancer susceptibility 
        screening. To standardize a fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) modification of the mutagen 
        sensitivity assay (MSA), scoring criteria were evaluated by web-based validation. Two hundred digital 
        FISH images were assigned random identification numbers. With this set of images, criteria for inclusion 
        of cells and measurement of the frequency of abnormal cells were evaluated by eight observers, all of 
        whom had five or more years of experience. Observers included doctoral and MS/BS level cytogeneticists, 
        and were drawn from a randomized pool of 54 volunteers. Questions addressed were: (1) how uniformly were 
        criteria applied to analysis of a standard digital FISH image set and (2) did concordance vary with 
        educational level? These data suggest inter-rater agreement within a factor of 2 for average breakage 
        frequency, but revealed greater variability in cell selection. These results aid in estimating the 
        components of assay variance due to definitions, technical parameters and biological variables.]]></val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyMethods</key>
        <val>Two hundred digital FISH images were assigned random identification numbers. With this set of 
        images, criteria for inclusion of cells and measurement of the frequency of abnormal cells were evaluated 
        by eight observers, all of whom had five or more years of experience.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyResults</key>
        <val>inter-rater agreement within a factor of 2 for average breakage frequency, but revealed greater 
        variability in cell selection. These results aid in estimating the components of assay variance due 
        to definitions, technical parameters and biological variables.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>GrantSupport</key>
        <val>Y1-CN-010-01</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolName</key>
        <val>54</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:NISTFishMSAData</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
        <val>63</val>   
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Unknown</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>
  
    <type id="urn:edrn:EVMSSELDIPhaseITOFMSData" name="EVMSSELDIPhaseITOFMSData">
    <repositoryPath>file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive</repositoryPath>
    <versionerClass>gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner</versionerClass>
    <description><![CDATA[The goal of the EDRN-Prostate-SELDI Investigational Collaboration (EPSIC) 
    is to use state-of-the-art protein profiling technology to further develop and validate a 
    serum-based screening method for prostate cancer.]]>
  </description>
    <metExtractors>
      <extractor
        class="gov.nasa.jpl.oodt.cas.filemgr.metadata.extractors.CoreMetExtractor">
        <configuration>
          <!--  you can optionally include the envReplace tag to turn on/off environment var replacement -->
          <property name="nsAware" value="true" />
          <property name="elementNs" value="CAS" />
          <property name="elements"
            value="ProductReceivedTime,ProductName,ProductId" />
        </configuration>
      </extractor>
    </metExtractors>
    <metadata>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataSetName</key>
        <val>EVMS Mass Spec data.</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>Date</key>
        <val>2008-06-24T20:12:00.000Z</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>LeadPI</key>
        <val>John Semmes</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianPhone</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>MethodDetails</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>AnalyticMethods</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyDesign</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>EligibilityCriteria</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ResultsAndColclusionSummary</key>
        <val>TBD</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DataCustodian</key>
        <val>Tina Xiao</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
        <val>Prostate and Urologic</val>
      </keyval>   
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyBackground</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Protein expression profiling for differences indicative of early cancer has promise for improving 
        diagnostics. This report describes the first stage of a National Cancer Institute/Early Detection Research 
        Network-sponsored multiinstitutional evaluation and validation of this approach for detection of prostate cancer.]]></val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyMethods</key>
        <val><![CDATA[Two sequential experimental phases were conducted to establish interlaboratory calibration and standardization 
        of the surface-enhanced laser desorption (SELDI) instrumental and assay platform output. We first established whether 
        the output from multiple calibrated Protein Biosystem II SELDI-ionization time-of-flight mass spectrometry (TOF-MS) 
        instruments demonstrated acceptable interlaboratory reproducibility. This was determined by measuring mass accuracy, 
        resolution, signal-to-noise ratio, and normalized intensity of three m/z "peaks" present in a standard pooled serum 
        sample. We next evaluated the ability of the calibrated and standardized instrumentation to accurately differentiate 
        between selected cases of prostate cancer and control by use of an algorithm developed from data derived from a single 
        site 2 years earlier.]]>
      </val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyResults</key>
        <val><![CDATA[When the described standard operating procedures were established at all laboratory sites, the across-laboratory 
        measurements revealed a CV for mass accuracy of 0.1 percent, signal-to-noise ratio of 40 percent, and normalized intensity of 15-36 percent 
        for the three pooled serum peaks. This was comparable to the intralaboratory measurements of the same peaks. The instrument 
        systems were then challenged with sera from a selected group of 14 cases and 14 controls. The classification agreement 
        between each site and the established decision algorithm were examined by use of both raw peak intensity boosting and ranked 
        peak intensity boosting. All six sites achieved perfect blinded classification for all samples when boosted alignment of raw 
        intensities was used. Four of six sites achieved perfect blinded classification with ranked intensities, with one site passing 
        the criteria of 26 of 28 correct and one site failing with 19 of 28 correct.]]>
      </val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>StudyConclusion</key>
        <val><![CDATA[These results demonstrate that "between-laboratory" reproducibility of SELDI-TOF-MS serum profiling approaches that of 
        "within-laboratory" reproducibility as determined by measuring discrete m/z peaks over time and across laboratories.]]></val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>ProtocolName</key>
        <val>109</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>DatasetId</key>
        <val>urn:edrn:EVMSSELDIPhaseITOFMSData</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>SiteName</key>
        <val>92</val>    
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
        <key>OrganSite</key>
        <val>Prostate</val>
      </keyval>
      <keyval>
      	<key>DataDisclaimer</key>
      	<val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this data and information does not constitute scientific publication. Data and/or information may contain errors or be incomplete.
NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.
NCI shall not be liable for any claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.
In accordance with scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI. 
      	</val>
      </keyval>
    </metadata>
  </type>
  
</cas:producttypes>
