<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- 
	Copyright (c) 2015 California Institute of Technology.
	ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. U.S. Government Sponsorship acknowledged.
	
	$Id$
	
	Author: Heather L. Kincaid, Luca Cinquini
	Description: Element policy for NIST Scott Pine data.
-->
<cas:producttypes xmlns:cas="http://oodt.jpl.nasa.gov/1.0/cas">
   <type id="urn:edrn:miRNAStudyPine" name="miRNAStudyPine">
      <description>
      Reference Samples to Assess Reproducibility of miRNA Measurements.
      </description>
      <repository path="file://[EDRN_REPO_HOME]/archive"/>
      <versioner class="gov.nasa.jpl.edrn.ecas.versioning.EDRNProductVersioner"/>
      <metadata>
         <keyval>
            <key>Date</key>
            <val>10/29/2015</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>ProtocolId</key>
            <val>410</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>DataCustodian</key>
            <val>Scott Pine</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>DataDisclaimer</key>
            <val>Data and information released from the National Cancer Institute (NCI) are provided on an "AS IS" basis, without warranty of any kind, including without limitation the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and non-infringement. Availability of this d\
ata and information does not constitute scientific publication. For information may contain errors or be incomplete.NCI and its employees make no representation or warranty, express or implied, including without limitation any warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose \
or warranties as to the identity or ownership of data or information, the quality, accuracy or completeness of data or information, or that the use of such data or information will not infringe any patent, intellectual property or proprietary rights of any party.NCI shall not be liable for an\
y claim for any loss, harm, illness or other damage or injury arising from access to or use of data or information, including without limitation any direct, indirect, incidental, exemplary, special or consequential damages, even if advised of the possibility of such damages.In accordance with\
 scientific standards, appropriate acknowledgment of NCI should be made in any publications or other disclosures concerning data or information made available by NCI.</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>OrganSite</key>
            <val>Liver, Placenta, Brain</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>CollaborativeGroup</key>
            <val>Lung and Upper Aerodigestive</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>DatasetId</key>
            <val>urn:edrn:miRNAStudyPine</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>AccessGrantedTo</key>
            <val>Plant National Institute of Standards and Technology</val>
            <val>Feng Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center</val>
            <val>Crichton JPL</val>
	    	<val>Srivastava National Cancer Institute</val>
            <val>Super User</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>SiteName</key>
            <val>611</val>
         </keyval>
        <keyval>
          <key>PubMedID</key>
          <val>NA</val>
        </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>QAState</key>
            <val>Accepted</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>DataCustodianEmail</key>
            <val>patrick.pine@nist.gov</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>DataSetName</key>
            <val>Reproducibility of miRNA Measurements</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>DatasetURL</key>
            <val></val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>DateDatasetFrozen</key>
            <val/>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>LeadPI</key>
            <val>Anne Plant</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>ProtocolName</key>
            <val>410</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>ResultsAndConclusionSummary</key>
            <val>
            </val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>MethodDetails</key>
            <val>
            Interlaboratory Comparison Repeatability and Reproducibility. Compare all the platforms to determine if miRNA signals vary across the dynamic range.
            </val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>PublishState</key>
            <val>yes</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>Discipline</key>
            <val>Genomics</val>
         </keyval>
         <keyval>
            <key>RecommendedSoftware</key>
            <val></val>
         </keyval>
      </metadata>
   </type>
</cas:producttypes>
